《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》 前情提要
KAT: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
我已心力交瘁
I was burnt out.
所以我就开始服用兴奋剂
I started taking stims.
这是什么?    兴奋剂
What are these? Stims.
看她的样子  已经吃了一把了
By the look of her, she's been taking them by the handful.
让我走 嗨 嗨
Let me go! Hey, hey!
你要知道  因为宿醉而简报迟到
You know, coming in late for a briefing 'cause you're hung over,
就已经很过分了
that's bad enough.
你还因此退出执行任务...
When you back out on a mission...
你听着  和你不同的是 我不会磕一把药之后
You see, unlike you, I don't take a bunch of pills,
还他妈的爬进驾驶舱 接着还他妈的着陆失败
and then climb in my cockpit so wired that I can't land the frakking ship.
星芭  你真是个耻辱
Starbuck, you're an embarrassment.
我想让你回到CIC
I need you back in the CIC.
没有你在那儿胁迫同僚
It just ain't the same without you in there,
就是不一样
intimidating the inmates.
噢  我可没有...
No, no.
只有12个赛昂人模型
There are only 12 Cylon models,
但在占领新卡布里卡的整个期间 只看到了7个
but in the entire occupation on New Caprica, I only saw seven.
另外的5个呢?
Who are the final five?
我不能说那个
I can't talk about that.
你知道她在说什么吗?
BALTAR: You have any idea what it's talking about?
绝大多数赛昂人都认为混合体的意识思维已经疯了
CAPRICA SIX: Most Cylons think the conscious mind of the Hybrid has simply gone mad
她所发出的声音对我们来说是无意义的
and the vocalizations we hear are meaningless.
但不是所有人都这么认为
But not everyone thinks that.
你要从你的日志中删除这个命令  执行命令
You'll delete the order from your logs. Execute.
没事了  没事了
It's okay, it's okay.
在生死之间
There is something beautiful,
有很瑰丽的景象
miraculous, between life and death.
你的意思是没有能食用的粮食可抢救了?
ROSLIN: You mean there's no food to be salvaged?
我们在这次意外污染发生前
What about the good food we had stored
储存的食物呢?
before we started inadvertently churning out the contaminated stuff?
新加工的受污染粮食直接进入了储藏系统
Well, the newly processed bad food went into the depleted storage system.
所有粮食都被污染了
Everything's tainted.
但是莎伦已经出发去寻找我们能加工的藻类了
But Sharon's out finding all this algae for us to process.
那东西很难吃  但基本上全是蛋白质
It's tough to choke down, but it's almost pure protein.
那如果莎伦回来报告说没有可以去那个星球的路怎么办?
What if Sharon comes back and reports there is no clear passage to this planet?
医生  那就有一个新问题了 我们还能撑多长时间?
Then the question is, Doc, how long can we survive?
按照我们现在的配给量 我觉得是7到10天
With the rations we've been on? I'd say seven to 10 days.
按计划  她什么时候回来?
ROSLIN: When is she due back?
她预期3小时前赶回
She was due three hours ago.
那里的辐射水平很高 但她很强壮  并且…
The radiation levels are high, but she's strong and she's...
她随时都可能赶回来的
She'll be here any moment.
抱歉  伙计们  我什么东西都没有
No, I'm sorry, you guys, I don't have anything.
来分给大家?
To share?
我告诉过你了  星芭  我什么东西都没有  别烦我了
I told you, Starbuck, I don't have anything. Get off my back, okay?
是啊  我看到你的小床上有蛋白质棒的
Yeah, I saw a protein bar on your cot.
我把它给了科特尔
I gave it to Cottle.
对呀!  就在我帮他解决之后
Right. Right after I gave him head.
你什么意思  我撒谎了?    哦 我不知道…
Oh, so, what, now I'm a liar? Oh, I don't know, if the shoe fits.
好了  好了  别吵!
All right, can it!
凯特  下来吧
Kat, get down here.
好了  他妈的  大家都吃吧
All right, for frak's sake, everybody, eat.
大家都被饿得变成妄想狂了
We're getting paranoid with this hunger.
这里  宝贝  吃这个
KAT: Here, baby, eat this.
我的天啊  真不错
Oh, my Gods, that's good.
去哪呢  戴安娜
BALTAR: Somewhere to be, D'Anna?
嘘  别把卡布里卡弄醒了
You'll wake Caprica.
听着  我情愿天天陪在你们俩身边
Look, I'd love to hang around with you two all day, but...
但是我还有些事要做
I have things to do.
我永远都不会明白你每天都独自干什么了
I'll never understand what you all do all day long,
像猫身上的跳蚤一样让人捉摸不定
living on this thing like fleas on a cat.
你认为她是去干什么了?
Where do you suppose she takes herself off to, then?
你不是第一个问这个问题的人了
You are not the only one asking that.
我不是?
I'm not?
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
她在忙着事呢
She's been doing things.
做事?
Doing things?
什么事?
What things?
好 动作快点
CREWMAN 1: Okay, let's make it faster.
抱歉 我扶住你了 中卫 小心
CREWMAN 2: Sorry about that. I've got you, Lieutenant. Watch your step.
走吧 我来拿头盔
Go ahead, I've got your helmet.
这边走 我来扶你 雅典娜
There you go. I've got you, Athena.
朝前走 让开路
Go ahead, walk her through.
百分之七浓度喷洒  移到右舷冲洗
Seven percent spray. Move around to the starboard side for wash-down.
二 十四
CREWMAN 3: Two-fourteen.
都好了 中尉 来这里 中尉
All the way down, Lieutenant. Right through here, Lieutenant.
来这儿
Right over here.
放射物已清除
Radiation negative.
别动
CREWMAN 4: Don't move!
有一条路穿过那个星团
There's a way through the star cluster.
我在另一边找到了那个星球
And I found the planet, on the other side.
我抓拍到了些照片
I skimmed it, I took photos.
正如我们所料  那里有很多海藻生长带
There's huge swaths of algae, just like we thought.
都变黑了
It's black.
她是赛昂人 她能承受那么大的辐射剂量
APOLLO: She's a Cylon. She can handle a radiation dose that big.
那只是我们觉得能!  谁去找下科特尔医生
We think. Someone call Cottle.
我很好
I'm fine.
对于你来说  也许是的
Maybe you are,
人类可能就做不到了
but a human might not be able to make it.
那现在我们怎么把数万人运过去?
So, then, how do we get tens of thousands of humans through there?
我们可以跳跃两次 在这个方位停一次
So we can make it through in two jumps with a stop right there.
是否可能只跳跃一次?
There's no solution with a single jump?
不行  这个星团太大了 都大到没法绕过去
No, the cluster's too big, and it's too big to go around, too.
但民用船只没有足够的装甲
But the civvie ships aren't shielded enough
跳跃到一个四周都是辐射的地方
to jump in the middle of all that radiation.
我觉得飞船上80%的人会因此而死掉
I would say 80% of the people on board would die.
我们能否只派卡拉狄加过去弄食物呢?
Can we send Galactica for food?
放在哪儿?  你什么意思?
And put it where? What do you mean?
那需要来回几十趟
It would take dozens of return trips.
每次离开 整个舰队就毫无防御能力
Each time we'd leave the fleet vulnerable to attack.
我们不能用把食物带给大家
We just can't bring the food to the people.
那假如我们把大家带去找食物呢?
What if we bring the people to the food?
把人们送上卡拉狄加
Put the people on Galactica.
把只配备基本船员的民用船只派过去
Send the civilian ships with skeleton crew,
给他们配备防辐射装束
give them radiation meds.
除非辐射不会把民用船只的导航系统烧坏
Except that the radiation would fry the civvie ships' nav systems.
那样他们在雷达上什么都看不到
They wouldn't be able to see squat on dradis.
他们如果进去了  想跳出来都难
There wouldn't even be a way to calculate a jump out.
比那还更糟
It's worse than that.
一旦你跳跃进去  能见度很低  你只能在那里漂泊
Once you jump in, the light is so blinding you begin to drift.
在找到坐标前  你在那早完蛋了
And before you can get your bearings, you're over there.
没有可视度 辐射还会让仪表失灵
APOLLO: No visual contact, instruments blinded by radiation.
他们会迷路的.他们肯定会被烧掉
They'd get lost, they'd burn up.
领航船
Pilot ship.
我们给每艘民用船只配备一架猛禽机
We pair a Raptor with each civilian ship.
猛禽机的导航系统抗辐射性要好一些
APOLLO: The Raptor navigation systems are hardened against nuclear strikes.
他们能承受得了这种辐射
They could handle the radiation.
每架猛禽机能领航一艘民用船只通过星团
Each Raptor could lead a civilian ship through the cluster,
然后他们再一起跳跃出去
then they both jump out together.
问题是要跳跃多少次?
The question is, how many jumps will it take?
来回共跳跃5次
APOLLO: Five round trips.
你们听到了吧 往返跳跃5次
You heard. Five round trips.
在我们跳过去的时候
On our outbound jumps,
我们每架猛禽机都负责向民用船只传送
we'll each be responsible for relaying jump coordinates
下一个跳跃点坐标
to our own specific civilian ship,
确保他们跳跃点的准确 并且要确保他们不离队
nailing them to their jump points and ensuring they don't drift off.
长官  当我们到那里时  要不要吃东西
Sir, are we gonna get fed when we get there?
最后嘛  当然要 但是要在我们找到并开始处理藻类后
Eventually, yes, but only after we find the algae and get it processed.
事实上
But the truth is that
辐射后的呕吐反应会让大家倒胃口
nausea from the radiation exposure will take care of our appetites.
你们都会被配发辐射剂量牌来跟踪你们受到的辐射量
You'll all be issued with radiation badges to track our exposure.
白色的  像这样的就没事
White, like this, you're okay.
当你暴露在辐射下时间越长  它就越黑
As your exposure increases, it'll darken.
当它变成这样了  那么你们就挂了
If it approaches this, then you'll be pulled from duty.
记住要随时观察剂量牌
Keep checking your badges.
这是每一个机师各自的责任 必须检查自己的剂量牌
It's every pilot's own responsibility to monitor their own badge.
星芭
Starbuck.
记住  这次任务我们全都独立飞行
Remember, we're all flying solo on this mission.
那就意味着  在你累了  或者
So that means there'll be nobody there to bitch-slap you
在你的机翼旁看到赛昂人时 没人能跟你配合搭档
if you start to get tired or start seeing little toasters on your wing.
我们会派发兴奋剂  到时候就用它
We'll be issuing stims, so use them.
什么?你疯了吗? 我们不能用兴奋剂
What? Are you crazy? We can't use stims.
凯特  你有什么疑问吗?
Kat, do you have a problem?
兴奋剂会加快我们的新陈代谢 很快会耗光我们的体力
Stims amp up your metabolism. We've got nothing to burn.
你让我们使用兴奋剂  我们会飞到民用船只里去的
You put stims in our systems, we're gonna be flying into the sides of the ships.
是真的吗?会让我们变得那么糟?
Is that true? They'd mess us up?
你过去喜欢用兴奋剂的  凯特
You used to like the stims, Kat.
好啦  那是对兴奋剂的个别看法
All right, personal discretion on the stims.
我们现在准备如刚才所说让第一波平民上船
We're taking the first load of civilians onboard as we speak.
就到这里 4小时以内开始
That's it. Skids up in four hours.
这里没有食物
DUALLA: There is no food here.
这艘船没有食品配给了
There are no rations anywhere on this ship.
如果有谁跟你们说哪里有食物  那是他们在骗你们
If someone told you there was food, they were lying.
如果你们离开这个区域  我们就会使用强制措施
If you leave this area, force will be used.
当我们通过星团
Once we get through the star cluster,
你们就可以返回原来所在的飞船
you will all be returned to your designated ships.
萨沙
Sasha.
跟上 直走向下到前面 对了
CREWMAN: Keep following, straight down to the front. That's right.
我不叫萨沙
My name isn't Sasha.
我是劳安・凯特瑞恩上尉 懂了吗?
My name is Captain Louanne Katraine, you understand me?
萨沙和你是上辈子的事情
Sasha and you were a lifetime ago.
好的 好的  就因为你现在有了杠杠了  对吗?
Right, right, 'cause you got this now, right?
不会再被罪人连累了  对吗?
No more hanging with the sinners, huh?
离我远点 你听懂了吗?
Stay away from me. Do you understand me?
他们知道你是什么样的人吗?
They even know who you really are?
噢  真巧在这里碰到你了
Oh, fancy bumping into you here.
你能相信我又迷路了吗?
Can you believe I'm lost again?
在这种地方我永远都找不到路
I never find my way around this place.
你到哪去了?
Where have you been?
我在和西蒙讨论去地球的下一步该怎么走
I've been talking with Simon about our next move toward Earth.
这个问题很明显有些争论
There's some debate about it, apparently.
当然了  如果我去问那个西蒙
Of course, if I spoke to the relevant Simon,
他能确认是你参加了这个会议的吗?
he'll actually ascertain you were at this meeting?
对不起  请再说一遍?
Beg your pardon?
我听说是你自己独自离开后 一人做事的
I hear that you've been going off by yourself, doing things.
真的吗?
Really?
那么  是谁告诉你关于我的事的呢?
Now who would tell you anything about my business?
那是真的了
So it's true?
卡布里卡?
Caprica?
你知不知道自己头发里有些干了的粘物?
Did you know you have some dried goo in your hair?
那是你复活时候出现的吧
That can happen when you resurrect.
你知道吗  现在我开始明白
Yeah, now I'm beginning to understand
这些天的下午  你对自己做了什么
just what you've been doing with yourself on all these afternoons.
你根本不了解你在指责我什么?
Do you have any idea what you are accusing me of?
当然知道
Yes.
故意的一次次的自杀
Intentionally killing yourself over and over
这样你就可以一次又一次地复活
so you can download over and over.
但死亡只像扇旋转门  对吧?
But that's just a revolving door, isn't it?
过来!
KAT: Come here!
你想干吗?
What do you want?
别紧张  宝贝  放松
Take it down a notch, baby. Relax.
我不是在寻找生意伙伴
I'm looking for a business partner.
我说过你他妈的离我远点
I told you to stay the frak away from me.
是啊  因为如果他们知道你的过去
Yeah, 'cause if they find out who you really are,
他们就会把你开除  甚至更糟
they'll kick you out of the service? Or worse?
现在  你是不是以为我想那么做?
Now, do you think I want that?
我不会那么做的  因为那样做了
I don't want that, 'cause if that happens,
谁来养我呢?
who's gonna feed me?
噢  拜托  你搞到了三支  你以为我不知道吗?
Oh, come on, you're getting three squares. You think I don't know that?
我们没有  我也没有隐瞒任何东西 恩佐
We don't. And I don't have anything stashed, Enzo.
是啊  你是没有
Yeah, sure, you don't.
噢  让我们重头开始吧  宝贝
Oh, we go back, baby.
什么时候照顾你也是犯法的了?
Since when is it a crime to take care of your own?
记住  我知道你是谁  我还知道怎么让你快乐
Remember, I know who you are, and I know how to make you happy.
把你的爪子拿开
Get your hands off of me.
上校!
Colonel.
继续
Go ahead.
检查一下
Check it out.
好的       欢迎回来  长官
MAN 1: All right. MAN 2: Welcome back, sir.
欢迎回来  长官    很高兴见到你 长官
MAN 3: Welcome back, sir. WOMAN 1: Good to see you, sir.
欢迎 很高兴见到你 长官 欢迎  长官
Welcome. It's good to see you, sir. Welcome, sir.
上校    很高心见到你 上校
Colonel. MAN 4: Good to see you, Colonel.
对 就这样    很高兴你回来
HOSHI: Yeah. That's it. WOMAN 2: Good to have you back.
好了
MAN 5: All right.
我们跟你了 长官
We're with you, sir.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
够了 你们这些家伙都没事做吗?
Enough! Don't you people have jobs to do?
欢迎回来  上校
Welcome back, Colonel.
上将
Admiral.
阿波罗  这是卡拉狄加  命令你发射猛禽机
Apollo, Galactica. Launch Raptors on your orders.
牧羊犬们  找到你要看管的"小羊羔"
APOLLO ON RADIO: Shepherds, find your sheep,
跟近点 别把他们弄丢了
stay close and never let them go.
这些家伙还要靠我们通过这段路呢
These crews are counting on us to guide them through.
阿波罗 星芭 抵达指定位置
STARBUCK: Apollo, Starbuck on station.
我看到Chiron号了
KAT ON RADIO: I've got visual on Chiron.
热狗 看到Adriatic号了
HOTDOG: Hotdog. Adriatic in sight.
好的
Okay.
当跳跃进星云以后 你们会分不清方向
When you jump into the cluster, you will be disoriented.
记住首先要做的
Take it one step at a time.
就是找到你们要带的民用船
Find your sheep, work the jump
然后计算下个跳跃点  把他们带出来
calculations and get them out.
记住  我们不能待到受最大辐射剂量的时候
Remember, we do not stay beyond our radiation dose limit.
阿波罗报告飞行员已准备好  长官
GAETA: Apollo reports pilots in position, sir.
命令他开始跳跃
Initiate jump on his command.
卡拉狄加会跟上
Galactica will follow.
是  长官
GAETA: Aye, aye, sir.
猛禽机  我是阿波罗  听我口令跳跃
Raptors, Apollo. We jump on my mark.
三
Three.
二  跳跃
Two. Jumping.
一...开始
One. Mark.
喔!这是什么?  我什么都看不到
Whoa! What is this? I can't see anything.
妈的
Frak.
找到你了!
Got you!
凯特  你找到你的了吗?
Kat, you got yours?
是的 阿波罗
KAT: Affirmative, Apollo.
只看到了Chrion号  传送坐标中
Only got eyes for the Chiron. Relaying coordinates.
飞行编队 我是阿波罗 我跟上了Thera Sita号了
Squadron, Apollo. I have Thera Sita.
马上给她传送坐标
Relaying jump coordinates to her right now.
阿波罗 我是星芭 我跟上我那艘了
STARBUCK: Apollo, Starbuck. I got mine.
妈的  我就在这地方干等着
Frak. I'm just barely holding on here.
我跟丢了 谁看见Adriatic号了?  他们没跳到预定坐标
I lost mine. Did anyone see the Adriatic? She has lost her jump coordinates.
热狗 无信号
APOLLO: Hotdog, negative.
无信号  热狗  没有Adriatic号的信号
Negative, Hotdog. Negative on Adriatic.
热狗  猛禽需要放松点控制
Hotdog, the Raptor needs to be under control, man.
放松点操作 这不是蝮蛇
Ease up with the stick. This is not a Viper, it's a Raptor.
妈的  妈的!
Frak it, frak it!
伙计 你能找到的 用眼睛去找
APOLLO: Find her, man! Get a visual!
阿波罗  这里是卡拉狄加
Apollo, it's Galactica Actual.
你们已达辐射剂量上限 必须跳跃走
You've reached your radiation dose limit. You've got to jump.
我们倒计时!      收到 卡拉狄加
Count us down. APOLLO: Roger that, Galactica.
不  阿波罗 请等下
No! No, Apollo, please, wait!
热狗  听我的  我们现在必须离开这儿
Hotdog, listen to me! We have to get out of here, now!
我能找到他们!    我能找到他们!  等等
I know I can find them! I can find them! Hold on!
请等等 不！    星芭  跟我倒计时一起跳跃
Please wait! No! Starbuck, jump on my mark.
不管是否找到飞船
With or without your ships!
请等等         1  2  3...
Please! One, two, three.
不  请等等!!      跳跃
No! Please! Wait! Mark!
我们不能这样离开他们!
We can't leave without her!
他妈的!他妈的!
Frak! Frak!
跳跃完成
Jump complete.
雷达恢复上线 报告舰壳中度损伤
Dradis is back online. Ship reports moderate hull damage.
卡拉狄加 阿波罗 第一波完成
APOLLO: Galactica, Apollo. First trip complete.
猛禽机降落
Raptors, land your birds,
并准备跳跃回来护送第二波民用船只
and prepare to jump back for the second group of civilians.
我们弄丢了Adriatic号
We lost the Adriatic.
这只是我们的第一波
It's only our first jump.
是  是啊
Yes, it is.
Carina号  我是凯特!  报告你的方位
Carina, Kat! Report your location!
凯特  阿波罗 你跟上Carina号了吗?
Kat, Apollo. Do you have the Carina?
没有!  辐射影响了我的导航!
Negative! Radiation's pissing on my nav.
我看不到
I can't see frak!
好吧 去找到她
Okay. Found her!
不 妈的     凯特！
No! Frak! APOLLO: Kat!
凯特  报告情况!
Kat, report!
真是该死的!
Gods damn it!
好了   凯特  时间到了 我们跳跃 听我口令
All right, Kat, Apollo! Time's up! We're jumping on my mark!
倒计时 3 2 1 开始!  没有Carina号!
Three, two, one, mark! Not without the Carina!
我跟丢了
I lost her.
好了  我们再次成功地让八艘船过去了
APOLLO: All right. We managed to get another eight ships through.
但是我们也弄丢了一艘
But we still lost one.
我们赶"羊"的技术是越来越好了
We've got to get better at tracking our sheep.
在跳跃的时候反应得很快
Quicker reaction times out of the jumps.
赛道别向不该发的船发送坐标
Racetrack, don't be calling out coordinates to the wrong ship.
我搞混了
I got mixed up.
检查你们的装备  检查完再检查
Keep checking your instruments and recheck them.
那些设备没点用
The instruments are crap.
好了
All right.
这就是第四次护送任务的总结了
That concludes Outbound Four.
现在是第四次休息了 一个个走
This is Return Four. One to go.
好了  休息一会
All right, get some rest.
来吧
Come on.
这是医生那来的报告
Here's a report from the Doc.
上百名陆战队员太虚弱无法工作
A hundred Marines too weak to work.
200多名等着打点滴
Two hundred more are ready to drop.
这是可以阻缓饥饿的
That's gonna slow down the harvest.
刚才这批平民看来搞出不少麻烦
The last batch of passengers kicked up some trouble.
你把这些家伙带到那一边
You get these people to the other side
他们想着会有做好的饭等着他们去吃
and they think there's a diner and a chef waiting to take their order.
我知道
I know.
他们何时才学会得到就必须要付出呢?
They got to learn we got to process the thing first, for frak's sake.
告诉他们这些话  让他们把自己肚子勒紧点
Try telling that to a bunch of empty stomachs.
我听说他们还在吃纸 是不是这样?
I hear they're still eating paper. Is that true?
不 纸张也短缺
No. Paper shortage.
不是个好消息!
Not a good sign.
的确不是  长官
No, sir.
当你重生的时候 你看到其余五名赛昂人的脸了吗?
So while you resurrect, do you see the faces of the Final Five?
没人见过他们
The ones that no one's seen?
你为什么对他们感兴趣?
Why do you want to know about them?
我可能是个赛昂人
I could be a Cylon.
我可能不再是那帮人的叛徒
I would stop being a traitor to one set of people
而是另一帮人的英雄
and be a hero to another,
并且有一个归属的地方
and have a place to belong.
你可以帮我了解我的使命
You would help me understand my destiny.
你看到我的脸了吗?
Have you seen my face?
你的脸?
Your face?
是  我的脸
Yes, my face.
我不记得了
I can't remember.
当我脑子还清楚记得的时候我试图把他们都画到纸上
I've been trying to get it all down on paper while it's still fresh in my mind,
但是总无法记得比这些更多的
but nothing much comes out.
我记得的都是些垃圾  我无法记住....
It's rubbish. I can't remember.
是赛昂人  还是人类
Cylons, humans...
是我们在探索我们是谁?
We're all just trying to discover who we are.
不是吗?
Aren't we?
嘿  恩佐
Okay. Hey, Enzo.
是的
Yeah?
我冒用了劳安・凯特瑞恩这个女孩的名字
I took the name Louanne Katraine from a girl
她在卡布里卡受袭两天前就死了
who died two days before the attack on Caprica.
这让我通过了背景调查
It got me through the background checks.
是啊  当时确实不容易  继续讲
Yeah, times were rough. Keep going.
我是个毒贩
I was a drug runner.
恩佐是我的上家
Enzo was my supplier.
你想干什么?  我们是贩毒的  行了吗?
What do you want? We were truckers, okay?
我们只是跑腿的
We just moved stuff.
民众
People.
你知道的  某些人以为那是赛昂人渗透进卡布里卡的方法
You see, some think that, that's the way that the Cylons infiltrated Caprica.
他们像种子一样撒遍整个殖民地外围地区
They seeded themselves throughout the outer colonies,
然后通过犯罪进入首都
and then they used criminals to get them into the capital.
不论是谁被发现帮助了赛昂人都会被认为是叛国者
Anyone who's found guilty of helping the Cylons is considered a traitor.
我们没有带赛昂人 你怎么知道没有呢?
We didn't carry Cylons. How do you know?
因为没人知道他们长得像我们
Because nobody knew that they looked like us.
那你怎么知道你没带过呢?
Then how do you know you didn't?
你怎么知道呢?
How do you know?
你认为我是个叛国者
You think I'm a traitor?
我认为我是个叛国者?
不 我不认为你是个叛国者
No. I don't think you're a traitor.
你是个聪明的年轻女人
You're a smart young woman.
那是老头子说的
That's what the old man said.
你只是没有聪明到面对真正的自我
You're just not smart enough to accept who you are.
你看  你通过欺骗的方法进入了我们这个好人帮
You see, you lied your way into the company of good people.
星芭  不要告诉上将
Starbuck, don't tell the Admiral.
求你
Please.
不要告诉他  否则我…    否则什么?
Please don't, or I... Or what?
星芭  请让我自己告诉他
Please. Just let me tell him myself.
请让我自己说
Please, just let me.
这样你同意吗?
Can you do that?
老天
Gods.
一度 名义角度
HYBRID: One degree. Angle nominal.
妇女儿童的海景肖像画心灵的深处
Seascape portrait of the woman-child, cavern of the soul.
压力下热度
Under pressure heat ratio.
进化让他们不再恐惧
lons of evolution have buried their fuse.
你就是在这里找到灵感?  不断地进行复活
So, this is where you got the idea to start intentionally downloading?
完形治疗
Gestalt therapy.
好  让我们看看能找到什么
All right, let's see what we can find out.
历史上  人和机器的联结
HYBRID: Throughout history, the nexus between man and machine
创造出了最具戏剧性的  最吸引人的
has spawned some of the most dramatic and compelling...
盖尤斯 你知道你在干什么吗?
Gaius, what do you think you're doing?
别碰它!
Don't touch it.
智能
Intelligence.
想火一样燃烧的思想
A mind that burns like a fire.
是的  我在
Yes. I'm here.
找到光芒旁的那只手
Find the hand that lies in the shadow of the light.
在母兽夫君的眼睛中
In the eye of the husband of the eye of the cow.
你还好吗?
You all right?
她只说些胡话  不是吗?
It just speaks nonsense, doesn't it?
我不认为她说的是胡话
I don't think anything it says is nonsense.
眼睛的丈夫 那眼睛是
The husband of the eye. The eye of the...
是赫拉的
Hera.
赫拉  有些时候被称为牛眼赫拉
Hera, sometimes referred to as cow-eyed Hera.
赫拉的丈夫...
And the husband of Hera...
是朱庇特
Is Jupiter.
朱庇特之眼
The Eye of Jupiter.
那是古代神书上的东西
That's written about in the ancient texts.
天呀
My God.
会不会在他们的神和我们的神之间有什么联系?
Could there be a connection between their Gods and ours?
那意味着什么?
What does it mean?
那是个方位
It's a location.
一颗隐藏于光芒中的行星
A planet hidden in the shadow of light.
可能是在一堆星团中
Probably a cluster of stars.
那会指引我们找到朱庇特之眼
That will lead us to the Eye of Jupiter.
并找到藏在光芒中的那只手
As to the hand hidden in the shadow of light,
可能是某种神器
it's probably some type of artifact.
手
Hand.
有五个手指
As in five.
代表五张面孔
Five faces.
现在我们需要做的就是找到那颗正确的行星
Now all we have to do is find the right planet.
在一个星团里
The right star cluster.
起来面对真正的自我
Accept who you are.
对
Yeah.
还记得我吗？
You remember me?
没错
Yeah.
没错  我当然记得你
Yeah, I remember you.
狗娘养的杂种
Thieving bastard.
你会毁了我的一切
You'll ruin everything I've got.
靠近我
Come here.
Faru Sadin号
Faru Sadin.
报告你的位置
Report your location.
凯特  你找到Faru Sadin号了吗?
Kat, you got Faru Sadin?
凯特?
Kat?
凯特  请回答!
Kat, report.
没有
Negative.
凯特…
Kat...
妈的!  我把Faru Sadin号弄丢了!
Frak! I've lost the Faru Sadin!
长官  舰队普遍报告船体损坏加剧
Sir, escalating damage reports, ship-wide.
维修小组报告出现连续的气压不稳定
Engineers are reporting a cascade of pressure failures.
跳跃点开始变得不稳定 我们必须赶快离开这里
Jump spot's become unstable. We've gotta get out of here.
打开全员频道
Open line.
是  长官
HOSHI: Aye, sir.
线路通了
Channel open.
阿波罗 这里是卡拉狄卡 全体实施跳跃
Apollo, Galactica Actual. Jump all.
重复一遍 全体实施跳跃
Repeat. Jump all.
好啦 上将的命令
All right, Admiral's calling it.
所有人听我的命令实施跳跃
Everyone, jump on my mark.
我不能再带丢另一艘飞船
I'm not losing another one.
3  2  1  实施跳跃!
Three, two, one. Mark!
阿波罗 星芭 我没看见凯特
Apollo, Starbuck. I don't see Kat.
报告情况
Report.
我们弄丢了Faru Sadin号还有一架猛禽
We're missing Faru Sadin and one Raptor.
是凯特的
GAETA: It's Kat.
她一定是没听到命令  还在那里
She must have missed the order. She's still out there.
见鬼
Damn.
Faru Sadin号  我是凯特  报告你的位置
Faru Sadin, this is Kat. Report your location.
他妈的!
Frak!
回来吧  孩子  回家来吧
TIGH: Come on, kid. Come on home.
是他们
HOSHI: It's them.
凯特把Faru Sadin号带回来了
She brought them home.
卡拉狄卡  我是凯特
Galactica, Kat.
任务完成
Mission accomplished.
他们说你想见我
They said you wanted to see me.
对
Yeah.
我觉得我们之间不应该象上次那样结束
I don't think we should end the way we ended.
听着  嗯
Listen.
每个人都...
Everybody is...
每个人都在被自己曾经的过错所折磨
Everybody is stuck with the things that they're not proud of.
那个  嗯  我的那个关于所谓好人的说法
And that... That thing about good people, I...
我不是那个意思
I didn't mean that.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
给你
Here.
拿着  这是安眠药
Take these. Sleeping pills.
这些已经足够了
Enough.
你想了断的话就用它吧
So, take them if you want.
谢谢
Thank you.
我得走了
I got to go.
上将  我...
Admiral, I...
我违背了您的命令  对不起
I know. I'm sorry.
我不是来这儿说教的
I'm not here to lecture.
我是来为你晋级的
I'm letting you know about a promotion.
我现在重新晋升你为CAG(空军指挥官)
I'm making you CAG again.
长官  你知道我是不会痊愈了的  对吗?
Sir, you know I'm not getting out of here, right?
它是你用实际行动赢得的
But you earned it.
你所做到的比面对枪林弹雨还要困难
What you did was harder than facing a bullet,
而你却为了拯救其他人的生命毫不犹豫地去做
and you did it without putting one other soul in harm's way.
如果换成是我  我都不知道自己能不能做到
I don't know if I could've done that.
我真的希望能够给予你更高的奖赏和鼓励
I wish there was something more that I could give you.
不 这足够好了
No. It's good.
我非常愿意成为CAG
I would like to be a CAG very much.
谢谢你
Thank you.
有件事情
There's a thing...
可能会让你后悔刚才的决定
A reason why you might not want to do this.
卡拉知道这件事
Kara knows what it is,
但我想亲自告诉你
but I wanted to tell you myself.
除了我已经知道的 我不想再知道更多了
I don't need to know anything other than what I already know.
当初你还是CAG的时候
When you were CAG,
你尽力保护你的队员
you protected your people,
你让他们感觉到安全进而英勇无畏
made them feel safe enough to be brave.
你刚才想要说的能改变你所做出的杰出贡献吗？
What you were gonna say doesn't change that.
你...你不走吗？
Are you... Are you staying?
嗯  我留下来陪你
Oh, I'm staying.
某种程度上我喜欢这间病房
I love this sick bay, in a way.
会让我想起我儿子Zak出生的地方
It reminds me of where my son, Zak, was born.
卡罗安妮当时是那么的高兴
Carolanne was so happy.
她以为
She was convinced,
两次怀的都是女孩
both times, that she was having a girl.
所以最后都是非常的惊喜
So it was a surprise at the end.
你也想要个女儿吗？
Did you want a girl, too?
是啊
Yeah.
三是个吉利的数字
Three's a good round number.